Hey guys, my name is Luís Eduardo.
I'm a developer at Zup Innovation company
that is revolutionizing the market of
technology with its Open-source projects
In this video we are going to talk about the Beagle
And I'll show you how to
create a small screen using Beagle on the
Backend of your application. Let's do it!
[Song]
Hello... First I will access the
documentation at the address "docs.usebeagle.io"
Select the Getting Started in the left column
then Using Beagle and "Backend" option
On this page we have all the usage configuration
for the Beagle and the settings for routes that
we use to access the screens we create
through Beagle.
So let's configure this step by step!
Our first step is to create a "Service"
So I must select the TAB
Spring boot in the documentation (link in description). Remembering that in the last
video we created a Backend project from
scrap with Spring boot and we added the
Beagle dependency. In this video we will
continue that implementation, configuring the
Beagle settings and creating a
Beagle screen in the Backend (BFF)
To create our Service, let's access the project code
we've already started (Beagle Backend). We click on SRC/main/kotlin and access
the package of our project. within this
package
let's create another package
called Service and here in this new package
let's create a class called "MyService"
let's create a class called "MyService" and
in this class we will use the
Spring @Service notation on the name of the
class. Here, we'll also create the "Builder" class, which will build our screen
This class will inherit the properties of a
Beagle interface called "ScreenBuilder"
which overrides the "build" method. This method is
responsible for returning to
Beagle screen. So let's implement class inheritance
ScreenBuilder and override the "build" method.
This method is the one that returns the screen we are going to create
(In this example we will implement the screen directly inside the build method)
So on line 10 we list the "build" method return
and let's implement our screen from the Screen component (which represents the screen)...
We'll start with the "child" attribute that it will receive
another component called that,
in turn will receive a list of components called
"Container". Inside the "Container" we have a
attribute called "children" which will receive a list of components
It is in this list of components that we will implement
the components that will appear on my screen (such as texts and buttons)
so today
let's create a Beagle text component (called Text)
To this first text component
let's add the value "Hello Beagle"
to the "text" attribute of the Beagle Text component
In this process we created our Service and
we created our small screen with the text "Hello Beagle"
Now, going back to our documentation, we'll see that
the next step is
create a class called "Controller"
select the Spring tab in the documentation and follow the code example
On Intellij
we must create a package called "controller" and
in this package create a
class called "MyController"
In the class we must use the notation
from Spring called "@RestController".
This class must have a
attribute in your constructor that
will receive the Service created previously
So I'm going to list the attribute in parentheses (in Kotlin's constructor)
And create a variable
call "myService" of type: "MyService"
After creating this variable, let's
create a "Route" in the MyController class
This route will follow the http.get method
and in it we must use the @GetMapping notation of Spring and
within the parentheses of this annotation
we must put the
name of our route, which will be "/screen".
Below the annotation, we must create a method
called "createScreen" which will be responsible for
instantiate the Service we created earlier.
The variable myService will return to
the screen we created with the text "Hello Beagle"
So below the notation we create
the method called "createScreen" and
as I said earlier, he's the one
will return to the Beagle screen
will return this small screen. So, in this
process, we create the class
"Controller" and now we must return to our
documentation and go to the next step.
Here we will make a configuration that is
very advantageous.
Whenever the backend "serializes" a Server Driven screen
a JSON is created with all attributes
of all the components used, however
attributes that have no value (and are null) do not need to be shown
which guarantees a leaner JSON.
So I should open the resources package
and the applicationProperties file
In it I must write the
two command lines. The first does not
appear null attributes
in the JSON that represents my screen
Line two makes the JSON
this route we created is
formatted and indented. Made this configuration
we must go back to the documentation
and follow the next step.
Our next step is to configure CORS
which means "CROSS ORIGIN RESOURCE SHARED".
It is the mechanism used by
browsers to transfer resources between
different backgrounds. So for applications
FRONTEND-WEB it is necessary to configure the CORS
in the backend
So let's make this configuration
To do so, we must select the SpringBoot tab
and copy the example configuration class.
To add it to the backend, we must
access the project package and
create a new package called "config".
It is in this package that we will create a
class called CorsConfig that
will contain the entire CORS configuration
So, after creating the class, we must paste the
configuration we got from the documentation...but
notice that the line points to an error
because we need to import this
Beagle constant that has an error
When importing the class of this constant
the error will disappear
and now we can go back to the documentation one last time
and see the last step
The last step is
configure http methods
In this step we will make the settings
for CROS to release requests
GET, PUT and POST type
In the documentation I will copy the "CorsConfig" class from this step
and overwrite the previous information in the CorsConfig class
and again we must import the Beagle constants.
And ready. We finished the necessary settings.
Now there is only
start our backend.
To start the project, select the file
"BeagleBackendAplication" and open this file
On line 9 click on the button to start the backend.
Which is a green start triangle.
and select RUN
This will start our project and it will
climb it locally. Once it's running
locally let's test our Backend
To do this, open your brownser
I open a tab and access our Backend via localhost
In the route type "localhost:8080/screen"
8080 is the port used
the route and "/screen" as we configured earlier
By pressing enter the browser
will show the JSON representing our screen
And that's it guys
any questions can be sent to our forum.
https://forum.zup.com.br/c/pt-br/beagle/16
Don't forget to subscribe to the channel, leave your like and that's it
the next