What's up guys, my name is Luís Eduardo
and I'm a developer here at Zup It
A company that is revolutionizing the
technology market with its open-source
projects. In this video we are going to talk about
Beagle, and show you how
you can contribute with Beagle's documentation.
you can contribute with Beagle's documentation
[Song]
First, I opened the
Beagle documentation at the link "docs.usebeagle.io"
And this is how it looks like,
in the left menu, we have an option to
"contribute". Here, we have a page
from Beagle Docs that will give you a
information on how to use the documentation tool we adopt,
the requirements you need to run it, etc. And
how can you document in Beagle Docs. So...
To document Beagle we use a tool called
HUGO that allows us to create static
page websites, using Markdown files.
To contribute, it is necessary to
fulfill some requirements that are listed here, at this page.
This page demonstrates how you can
contribute to the documentation and also how
to use Hugo shortcodes section. The Shortcodes
are new visual elements and interfaces
that can be used to build a better organized
documentation. Unfortunately, Markdown syntax won't
offer all resources necessary to best
organize elements in a documentation section, so
through these Shortcodes, you will have access
tp more features and elements to use when building
a documentation page, in this example, you can refer
links, show Alerts like hints, show
images, embed videos, among other things!
So I'm going back here for the "overview"
from Docs and now let's talk
a little bit about how you can contribute...
There are two ways you can
contribute to the Documentation. The first is here
in the upper right corner, where we list a
small menu with some options. So through this menu
you can edit the page you are on, or
create another page. You can also
create an "issue" to suggest an
improvement on this page, or even correct any error that
you may have found in the documentation. You may
create an "issue" for our team to analyze
and maybe even add your suggestion. So this is
the first way for you to contribute
with our Docs! But there is
another to contribute
which is through the
Beagle repository on GitHub.
You can open the "beagle-docs", which is where
the Beagle documentation repository is located, and here you can
fork the repository by cloning it
and them open it locally in any
text editor of your choice. Those
are the two ways to contribute, but there are
some points that require our attention. When looking at the top menu
there is an option to change the Beagle Version you wish the documentation for
When we published this video, we had versions 1.5, 1.6, 1.7
So, how does it work? If you are
using Beagle version 1.5 in your project
you will open the documentation in 1.5
to see the Beagle features at version 1.5. If
you are using Beagle version 1.6
you will open the documentation in 1.6 and
so on, so forth. In this first
menu option, called "Edit this page", you will be able to change
the contents for
the latest Beagle version, which in this example was the
1.7... So, how do I contribute
on version 1.5 or 1.6? Which are older versions
You will be able to do it by
forking our repository. So, you must clone our
repository on your machine and open it
in any text editor, in the example here
I will use
the Visual Studio. Before we start, lets
make this example clear...
Let's assume I'm going to contribute to the
documentation version 1.5. To
make a change to the 1.5 version I need to access the
branch release-v1.5 (locally) and
create another branch from it
That i'm able to modify and create a pull request to merge it
into the branch release-v1.5. This goes for all versions
in our documentation. So if I want to contribute to the
version 1.6, I must access the release
branch-v1.6 and create a new
branch from it and again open a pull request
for the release branch 1.6 right? It is important to make
this details very clear so you could
contribute in the correct
way. I'm opening my editor here...
the Visual Studio and them I will
open the documentation. I already have
cloned the repository here, So I have
it locally on my machine. I will
open a new project here, Open a folder and
select the documentation folder
Open it and them the Visual Studio will
list the project for me. Here, notice the
"content" folder in my project structure
this is the folder that contains all the
documentation content separated by language; which is Portuguese,
in the PT folder... So if I want to edit a
content in Portuguese, I'll edit
in this folder. So I'm going to open the PT folder and I
will edit the "overview" file that
is the one we were seeing.
If I want to edit a page
in English, I'm going to open the EN folder
and open the MD file I want to
edit or even create a new one, ok? So this is
the way you can contribute
with our Documentation and that's it guys! Thank you very much
for watching this video, and don't forget to
leave your like, and subscribe to the channel and
to see you next time!